Guide to the Gerrit Lansing Papers YCAL MSS 469
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- August 2019 acquisition, 1814–2018; Bulk, 1950–2018; 8; 53.85 Linear Feet (66 boxes)
  - Occult Papers
    - Occult Studies
      - Correspondence
        - Shepard, Joseph, 2013 (Box 31)
        - Staley, Michael, 2006, undated (Box 31)
        - Stone, Daniel, 1980 (Box 31)
        - Wilby, Basil, 1967 (Box 31)
        - Williams, David, 1967 (Box 31)
      - Other Papers
        Includes essays and lecture notes by Lansing, tarot cards, notes on tarot and yoga, order forms and receipts for occult books, and a collection of runes and ogham staves.
        Arranged alphabetically by folder title, with a box of runes and ogham staves filed at the end of the sequence.
        - "Chapatnath and Geroka Bodh", undated (Box 31)
        - Crowley photocopy with Lansing notes [bound copy of Little Essays Toward Truth by Alistair Crowley], undated (Box 31)
        - Essay on alchemy, undated (Box 31)
        - Essay on astrology, undated (Box 31)
        - Essay on Badianus manuscript, undated (Box 31)
        - Hand-colored Paul Foster Case tarot cards, undated (Box 31)
        - Hand-copied "The Fleeing Atalanta", undated (Box 31)
        - Hand-drawn rune cards, undated; 2 Folders (Box 31)
        - Magic lecture, circa 2012 (Box 31)
        - Magick Notebook, undated (Box 31)
        - Notes, 1986-2007, undated (Box 31)
        - Notes on introduction to new edition of Etidorhpa, 2017 (Box 31)
        - Notes on Meyrink, undated (Box 31)
        - Notes on mudras and yogic education, undated (Box 31)
        - Notes on yoga for Ken Irby, undated (Box 31)
        - Numerological correspondences, undated (Box 31)
        - Occult order forms, mailers, receipts, 1989-2014, undated (Box 31)
        - Origin of magic name, undated (Box 31)
        - Photocopied diagrams for [Robert] Podgurski manuscript, undated (Box 30)
        - Reader's report for [Samuel] Weiser, circa 1994 (Box 31)
        - Tarot notebook, undated (Box 31)
        - Theatr. Chemicum., undated (Box 31)
        - Yoga binder, undated; 2 Folders (Box 31)
        - Ogham staves [stored in raffia cloth bag] (Box 32)
        - Wooden runes [stored in plastic bag] (Box 32)
        - Ceramic runes [stored in Scrabble bag] (Box 32)
        - Stone runes [stored in purple and black bags] (Box 32)
    - Astrology
      Primarily astrological and natal charts for Lansing and others.
      - Astrological data, undated (Box 31)
      - Astrological diagram, undated (Box 31)
      - Astrological charts [for Lansing], 1953–2012 (Box 31)
      - Astrological and natal charts [for others], 1966–2014; 16 Folders (Box 31)
      - Astrological and natal charts: unknown, circa 1970s-2007 (Box 31)
      - Astrological and natal charts [removed from binder], circa 1970s-1999 (Box 31)
      - Letter from Lansing to Oscar Weber, 1965 (Box 31)
      - Natal charts and natal chart sheets [removed from binder], undated (Box 31)
  - Annotated Books
    This subseries contains books on the occult, poetry, art, and other topics, as well as novels and biographies, annotated by Gerrit Lansing.
    Organized into two groupings: Occult, and Non-occult. Arranged alphabetically by author, or title if the author is unknown.
    - Occult
      - Avens, Roberts. The New Gnosis (Box 33)
      - Bentov, Itzhak. Stalking the Wild Pendulum (Box 33)
      - Blavatsky, H. P.
        - An Abridgement of the Secret Doctrine (Box 33)
        - Isis Unveiled vols. 1+2 (Box 33)
      - Bleakley, Alan. Fruits of the Moon Tree: The Medicine Wheel & Transpersonal Psychology (Box 33)
      - Boehme, Jacob. Personal Christianity (Box 33)
      - Bonner, John. Qabalah: A Primer (Box 33)
      - Brinton, Howard H. The Mystic Will: Based on a Study of the Philosophy of Jacob Boehme (Box 33)
      - Burckhardt, Titus. Alchemy (Box 33)
      - Case, Paul Foster. The Tarot (Box 33)
      - Colquhoun, Ithell. Sword of Wisdom (Box 33)
      - Cornford, Francis MacDonald. Plato and Parmenides (Box 33)
      - Eliade, Mircea.
        - Forgerons et Alchimistes (Box 33)
          Inscribed by the author: "Pour M. Gerrit Y. Lansing, ce petit livre sur le "origines" de l'achimie – avec l'hommage de l'auteur. Mircea Eliade New York, Juie 1957."
        - The Forge and the Crucible (Box 33)
      - von Franz, Marie-Louise. Alchemy (Box 35)
      - Fries, Jan. Helrunar: A manual of rune magick (Box 33)
      - González-Wippler, Migene. Santería (Box 35)
      - Graves, Robert. The White Goddess (Box 33)
      - Griaule, Marcel. Conversations with Ogotommêli (Box 33)
      - Hayward, Jeremy W. Perceiving Ordinary Magic (Box 34)
      - Hoeller, Stephan A. The Gnostic Jung (Box 34)
      - Howard, Michael. The Book of Fallen Angels (Box 34)
      - Jackson, Nigel, and Michael Howard. The Pillars of Tubal-Cain (Box 34)
      - King, C.W. The Gnostics and Their Remains (Box 34)
      - King, Francis. Tantra for Westerners (Box 34)
      - Levi, Eliphas. Transcendental Magic (trans. A.E. Waite) (Box 34)
      - von List, Guido. The Secret of the Runes (Flowers, ed.) (Box 35)
      - Massey, Gerald. Gerald Massey's Lectures (Box 34)
      - Michell, John. The New View Over Atlantis (Box 34)
      - Parfitt, Will. The Living Qabalah (Box 34)
      - Pennick, Nigel.
        - Rune Magic: The History and Practice of Ancient Runic Traditions (Box 34)
        - Runic Astrology (Box 34)
      - Regardie, Israel. The Tree of Life: A Study in Magic (Box 34)
      - Sellers, Jane B. The Death of Gods in Ancient Egypt (Box 34)
      - Shou, Peryt. The Edda as Key to the Coming Age (Box 34)
      - Steiner, Rudolf.
        - An Outline of Occult Science (Box 34)
        - Cosmic Memory: Atlantis and Lemuria (Box 34)
        - The Philosophy of Freedom (Box 34)
      - Straughn, R.A. Meditation Techniques of the Kabalists, Vedantins and Taoists (Box 34)
      - Summers, Catherine, and Julian Vayne. Seeds of Magick: An Exposé of Modern Occult Practices (Box 34)
      - Thorsson, Edred.
        - Rune Might (Box 35)
        - Runelore (Box 35)
      - Waldberg, Michel. Gurdjieff: An Approach to His Ideas (Box 35)
      - Walker, Barbara G. The Secrets of the Tarot (Box 35)
      - Yates, Frances A.
        - Giordano Bruno and the Hermetic Tradition (Box 35)
        - The Occult Philosophy in the Elizabethan Age (Box 35)
        - The Rosicrucian Enlightenment (Box 35)
    - Non-occult
      - Ahearn, Barry. Zukofsky's "A" (Box 36)
      - Ammons, A. R. Sphere: The Form of a Motion (Box 36)
      - Austin, J. L. How to Do Things with Words (Box 36)
      - Baran, Paul A., and Paul M. Sweezy. Monopoly Capital (Box 36)
      - Barfield, Owen.
        - Poetic Diction: A Study in Meaning (Box 36)
        - The Rediscovery of Meaning (Box 36)
      - Bataille, Georges. Visions of Excess (Box 36)
      - Baudrillard, Jean. The Mirror of Production (Box 36)
      - Behler, Ernst, ed. Philosophy of German Idealism (Box 36)
      - Bergson, Henri.
        - The Creative Mind (Box 36)
        - Time and Free Will (Box 36)
      - Berkeley, George. Principles, Dialogues, and Correspondences (Box 36)
      - Binswanger, Ludwig. Being in the World (Box 36)
      - Boundary 2 (Jack Spicer issue), vol. VI, no. 1 (Box 36)
      - Breton, André. Arcane 17 (Box 36)
      - Burke, Kenneth. Permanence and Change (Box 36)
      - Butler, Judith. Gender Trouble: Feminism and the Subversion of Identity (Box 36)
      - Byrd, Don. The Poetics of Common Knowledge (Box 36)
      - Carpenter, Edward. Pagan & Christian Creeds: Their Origin and Meaning (Box 36)
        Note on endpaper: "first read at Harvard, c. 1947 in course on Europe's intellectual history by Taylor, in history dept."
      - Casey, Edward S. Imagining: A Phenomenological Study (Box 36)
      - Chase, Richard. The American Novel and Its Tradition (Box 37)
      - Clarke, John. Feathers to Iron (Box 37)
      - Collingwood, R.G. The Principles of Art (Box 37)
      - Coomaraswamy, Ananda K. Christian and Oriental Philosophy of Art (Box 37)
      - Creeley, Robert. A Quick Graph: Collected Notes & Essays (Box 37)
      - de Certeau, Michel.
        - Heterologies (Box 37)
        - The Practice of Everyday Life (Box 37)
      - de Riencourt, Amaury.
        - The American Empire (Box 37)
        - The Soul of China (Box 37)
      - Deleuze, Gilles, and Félix Guattari.
        - Anti-Oedipus (Box 37)
        - A Thousand Plateaus (Box 37)
      - Dewey, John. Art as Experience (Box 37)
      - Dick, Philip K. Valis (Box 37)
      - Dickie, George. Aesthetics: An Introduction (Box 37)
      - Doniger O'Flaherty, Wendy. The Rig Veda (Box 37)
      - Duberman, Martin. Black Mountain: An Exploration in Community (Box 38)
      - Ehrenzweig, Anton. The Hidden Order of Art (Box 38)
      - Emerson, R.W. Essays: Second Series (Box 38)
      - Erbés, Philip H. Unwritten Meanings of Words (Box 38)
      - Fichte, J. G.
        - Science of Knowledge (Box 38)
        - The Way towards the Blessed Way of Life; or, The Doctrine of Religion (Box 38)
      - Fletcher, Angus. A New Theory for American Poetry (Box 38)
      - Fries, Jan. Living Midnight: Three Movements of the Tao (Box 38)
      - Frye, Northrop. Fearful Symmetry (Box 38)
      - Fung Yu-Lan.
        - A History of Chinese Philosophy, Vol. II (Box 38)
        - A Short History of Chinese Philosophy (Box 38)
      - Gajjar, Bharat. Yoga for Union with God, Self Realization and Good Health (Box 38)
      - Gardiner, Patrick. Schopenhauer (Box 38)
      - Goddard, David. The Sacred Magic of the Angels (Box 38)
      - Goethe, Johann Wolfgang. The Sorrows of Young Werther (Box 38)
      - Grousset, René. The Rise and Splendour of the Chinese Empire (Box 38)
      - Guénon, René. The Great Triad (Box 38)
      - Gutmann, James. Schelling: Of Human Freedom (Box 39)
      - Hegel, G. W. F.
        - Hegel: On the Arts ed., Henry Paolucci (Box 39)
        - On Art, Religion, Philosophy (Box 39)
        - Reason in History (Box 39)
      - Heidegger, Martin.
        - Discourse on Thinking (Box 39)
        - An Introduction to Metaphysics (Box 39)
        - Poetry, Language, Thought (Box 39)
        - What Is Called Thinking? (Box 39)
      - Hillman, James. Re-Visioning Psychology (Box 39)
      - Hippocratic Writings (Box 39)
      - Hiriyanna, M. Outlines of Indian Philosophy (Box 39)
      - Holbrook, Bruce. The Stone Monkey: An Alternative, Chinese-Scientific, Reality (Box 39)
      - Hollingdale, R. J. Nietzsche: The Man and His Philosophy (Box 39)
      - Hough, Robert L. Literary Criticism of Edgar Allan Poe (Box 39)
      - Huberman, Leo. Man's Worldly Goods (Box 39)
      - Hugo, Victor. Les Contemplations (Box 39)
      - James, Henry.
        - The Ambassadors (Box 39)
        - The Golden Bowl (Box 39)
        - The Tragic Muse (Box 40)
        - The Wings of the Dove (Box 40)
      - Johnson, Raynor C. Nurslings of Immortality (Box 40)
      - Johnson, W. R. The Idea of the Lyric (Box 40)
      - Jones, David. The Anathemata (Box 40)
      - Joyce, James. Finnegan's Wake (Box 40)
      - Junger, Ernst. On the Marble Cliffs (Box 40)
      - Kant, Immanuel. Prolegomena to Any Future Metaphysics (Box 40)
      - Kaptchuk, Ted. The Web Has No Weaver: Understanding Chinese Medicine (Box 40)
      - Kavan, Anna. Sleep Has This House (Box 40)
      - Kingsland, Kevin and Venika. Complete Hatha Yoga (Box 40)
      - Kohn, Livia, ed. The Taoist Experience (Box 40)
      - Langer, Suzanne K.
        - Feeling and Form (Box 40)
        - Mind: An Essay on Human Feeling (Box 40)
      - Lautréamont. Maldoror (Box 40)
      - Lears, Jackson. No Place of Grace: Antimodernism and the Transformation of American Culture, 1880-1920 (Box 41)
      - Lippard, Lucy R. Surrealists on Art (Box 41)
      - Logan, James Venable. The Poetry and Aesthetics of Erasmus Darwin (Box 41)
      - Lowe, Victor. Understanding Whitehead (Box 41)
      - Luk, Charles. (Lu K'uan Yü)
        - The Secrets of Chinese Meditation (Box 41)
        - Taoist Yoga: Alchemy and Immortality (Box 41)
      - Lysebeth, Andre van. Pranayama (Box 41)
      - Marcel, Gabriel.
        - Homo Viator (Box 41)
        - The Philosophy of Existentialism (Box 41)
      - Marías, Julían. History of Philosophy (Box 41)
      - Matthiessen, F. O. American Renaissance (Box 41)
      - Mays, W. The Philosophy of Whitehead (Box 41)
      - Meisel, James H.
        - The Myth of the Ruling Class: Gaetano Mosca and the Elite (Box 41)
        - Pareto & Mosca (Box 41)
      - Merleau-Ponty, Maurice. The Primacy of Perception (Box 41)
      - Miller, Henry. The Cosmological Eye (Box 41)
      - Moon, Michael. Disseminating Whitman (Box 41)
      - Moorman, Mary. William Wordsworth: A Biography, the Early Years 1770-1803 (Box 41)
      - Naydler, Jeremy. Shamanic Wisdom in the Pyramid Texts (Box 42)
      - Nietzsche, Friedrich. The Will to Power (Box 42)
      - Novalis. Henry von Ofterdinen (Box 42)
      - Olson, Charles.
        - The Maximus Poems (Box 42)
        - The Special View of History (Box 42)
      - Osborne, Arthur, ed. The Collected Works of Ramana Maharshi (Box 42)
      - Peckham, Morse. Man's Rage for Chaos: Biology, Behavior & the Arts (Box 42)
      - Peirce, C. P. Philosophical Writings of Peirce, ed., Justus Buchler (Box 42)
      - Plant, Sadie. The Most Radical Gesture (Box 42)
      - Polanyi, Michael. Knowing and Being (Box 42)
      - Pound, Ezra. The Cantos of Ezra Pound (Box 42)
      - Pratyagatmananda, Swami. Japasutram: The Science of Creative Sound (Box 42)
      - Ramanujan, A.K., ed. Speaking of Siva (Box 42)
      - Reich, Wilhelm. Ether, God and Evil, Cosmic Superimposition (Box 42)
      - Ricardou, Jean. Problèmes du nouveau roman (Box 42)
      - Schiller, Friedrich. On Aesthetic Education of Man in A Series of Letters (Box 42)
      - Schopenhauer, Arthur.
        - On the Fourfold Root of the Principle of Sufficient Reason and On the Will of Nature (Box 42)
        - The World as Will and Representation (Box 42)
      - Sebottendorf, R. v. The Practice of the Ancient Turkish Freemasons (Box 42)
      - Sekida, Katsuki. Zen Training (Box 42)
      - Sherburne, Donald W., ed. A Key's to Whitehead's Process and Reality (Box 42)
      - Sinnett, A. P. Esoteric Buddhism (Box 43)
      - Spengler, Oswald. Decline of the West (Box 43)
      - Spicer, Jack. The Collected Books of Jack Spicer (Box 43)
      - Staal, Frits. Exploring Mysticism (Box 43)
      - Stein, Gertrude.
        - The Geographical History of America (Box 43)
        - Writings and Lectures: 1909-1945 (Box 43)
      - Stringer, E. T. The Secret of the Gods: An Outline of Tellurianism (Box 43)
      - Sweetser, Wesley D. Arthur Machen (Box 43)
      - The Chief Works of Spinoza, trans. R. H. M. Elwes, Vol. II (Box 43)
      - The Tao of Health, Longevity, and Immortality: The Teachings of Immortals Chung and Lü (Box 43)
      - Valéry, Paul. The Art of Poetry (Box 43)
      - Van Dusen, Wilson. The Natural Depth In Man (Box 43)
      - Versluis, Arthur. The Egyptian Mysteries (Box 43)
      - Wallace, William. The Logic of Hegel (Box 43)
      - Wallack, F. Bradford. The Epochal Nature of Process in Whitehead's Metaphysics (Box 44)
      - Watson, Burton. Chinese Rhyme-Prose (Box 44)
      - Watts, Alan W. The Supreme Identity (Box 44)
      - Welch, Holmes. Taoism: The Parting of the Way (Box 44)
      - Whitehead, Alfred N.
        - Adventures of Ideas (Box 44)
        - Modes of Thought (Box 44)
        - Process and Reality (Box 44)
        - The Concept of Nature (Box 44)
        - Science and the Modern World (Box 44)
      - Whyte, Lancelot Law. The Unconscious Before Freud (Box 44)
      - Wild, John, ed. Spinoza Selections (Box 44)
      - Williams, Raymond. The Country and the City (Box 44)
      - Williams, W. C.
        - Paterson (Box 44)
        - Selected Essays (Box 44)
      - Wind, Edgar. Pagan Mysteries in the Renaissance (Box 44)
      - Wittgenstein, Ludwig. Philosophical Investigations (Box 44)
      - Wolff, Kurt, ed. The Sociology of Georg Simmel (Box 44)
      - Yingling, Thomas E. Hart Crane (Box 44)
      - Ziarek, Krzysztof. Inflected Language: Toward A Hermeneutics of Nearness: Heidegger, Levinas, Stevens, Celan (Box 44)
      - Zukofsky, Louis A. California: 1978 (Box 44)
  - Personal Papers
    This subseries includes materials related to Gerrit Lansing's early life and education, legal and medical records, family histories, genealogical scrapbooks, and papers of his father Charles B. Lansing and sister Alice J. Lansing. There are also photographs of Lansing, Deryk Burton, family, and friends, and artworks and music compositions created by or given to Lansing.
    Organized into five groupings: Personal, Financial, and Legal Records, Family Papers, Photographs, Artwork and Unique Books, and Music.
    - Personal, Financial, and Legal Records
      Contains documents related to Gerrit Lansing's birth and early life, including ink impressions of his feet as a baby, a sealed envelope of his hair at 10 months old, and grade school report cards. There are additionally diplomas and a yearbook from Harvard and Columbia; an embossed Bible; a small amount of financial and medical records; and a guestbook from Lansing's memorial service.
      - Address books, undated; 5 Folders (Box 45)
      - Bible [embossed with Lansing's name] (Box 46)
      - Birth and baptism certificates, telegrams, other birth-related documents, 1928–1993 (Box 45)
        Includes ink impressions of Lansing's feet as a baby, and a sealed envelope of his hair at 10 months old.
      - Columbia University Master of Arts diploma, 1955 (Box 47)
      - Harvard Album (yearbook), 1949 (Box 48)
      - Harvard College diploma, 1949 (Box 47)
      - Juvenile writings, valentines, circa 1936, undated (Box 45)
      - Legal correspondence, 1980–1982 (Box 45)
      - Medical records, 1928–2018 (Box 45)
      - Memorial service guestbook, 2018 (Box 45)
      - Misc. personal documents, 1976-1982, undated (Box 45)
      - Passports, 1949, 1985 (Box 45)
      - Report Cards 4-8, Park School of Cleveland, 1936–1940 (Box 45)
      - Selective Service Records, 1946–1950 (Box 45)
    - Family Papers
      Contains scrapbooks and files related to Lansing family genealogy, and Charles B. Lansing's business and philanthropic interests and yachts, as well as stamps and writings of Alice B. Lansing. Also included is an 1861 Yale yearbook belonging to Frank E. Kernochan, an ancestor of Gerrit Lansing.
      - Alice J. Lansing
        - Calling card, monogram stamps, undated (Box 46)
        - Correspondence regarding W. L. Palmer paintings [includes negatives], 1983 (Box 45)
        - Poetry notebook, undated (Box 48)
        - Writings, school papers, 1936, undated (Box 45)
      - Charles B. Lansing
        - Business and employment, 1948–1962 (Box 45)
        - Business scrapbook, 1919–1974 (Box 49)
        - Case Western memorial resolution, 1978–1979 (Box 47)
        - Case Western memorial scrapbook, 1927–1967; 2 Folders (Box 45)
        - "For God, for Country, and for Yale," pamphlet by George S. Brady, with letter to Charles B. Lansing, 1969 (Box 45)
        - History of the Twelfth Engineers [History of Lansing's WWI unit], 1919 (Box 48)
        - "History of the World, Volume I" [autograph manuscript, bound], 1947 (Box 50 (Oversize))
        - "The Lansing Ships," Vol. 1, 1954? (Box 51)
          Account of voyages and ships owned by Lansing from 1927 to 1954. There are photographs tipped in throughout the volume.
        - "The Lansing Ships," Vol. 2, 1965 (Box 51)
          Accounts of voyages from 1955 to 1965, a 1963 trip to India, and Lansing's World War I memories.
        - Log book ketch Big Dipper, 1948–1956 (Box 45)
        - Log book yacht Lady Luck, 1956–1958 (Box 45)
        - War memories, undated (Box 45)
      - Francis Morgan: An Early Virginia Burgess and Some of his Descendants, 1920 (Box 48)
      - Genealogy, family trees, correspondence, etc., 1898–1991; 2 Folders (Box 45)
      - Genealogy, family trees, correspondence, etc., 1898–1991 (Box 47)
      - Genealogy of the Lansing Family in America 1640-1985 "focusing in the Albany Lansings" [privately printed genealogy] (Box 45)
      - Genealogy scrapbook - Lansing, undated (Box 52)
      - Genealogy scrapbook - "A Chapter in Family History" by John McIlevene, undated (Box 52)
      - Gerrit Lansing baby book, 1928-circa 1931 (Box 45)
      - Lansingburgh, New York, 1771-1971 [printed by the Lansingburgh Historical Society] (Box 45)
      - Newspaper clippings, other family history, 1814–1987; 2 Folders (Box 45)
      - Yale yearbook, 1861 (Box 53)
    - Photographs
      Includes Lansing family photographs dating from the 1850s, and photographs of Gerrit Lansing, Deryk Burton, and writers, artists, and musicians, such as Diane di Prima, Kenward Elmslie, Robert Kelly, Harry Martin, and John Wieners. Many images also depict houses, boats, pets, readings, and parties.
      Arranged alphabetically by folder title, with framed photographs filed at the end of the sequence.
      - Abraxis Bookstore, 1980s? (Box 54)
      - Bainbridge High School graduation photograph, 1945 (Box 47)
      - Castle Era, 1963-1964, undated (Box 54)
      - Castle Era, 1960s? (Box 54)
      - Castle Era, 1960s? (Box 55)
        Restricted fragile material. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - Cats through the ages, 1948–1987 (Box 54)
      - Charles Olson [includes negatives], 1963-1965, undated (Box 54)
      - Deryk Burton [includes obituary], circa 1950s-1997; 2 Folders (Box 54)
      - [Family], 1891–1981 (Box 54)
      - [Family], 1891–1981 (Box 47)
      - [Family, housed in leather folio], circa 1890s (Box 54)
      - [Friends], circa 1950s-2009 (Box 54)
        Includes a photograph of Jack Spicer, Robin Blager, Carolyn Dunn, Joe Dunn, and Robert Duncan, taken by Kent Bowker.
      - [Friends and family?], circa 1950s-2009 (Box 54)
        Includes a photograph of Lansing taken by Gerard Malanga, and copies of photos of various people, among them John McGavern and Douglas Stafford.
      - [Friends and family?], 1959-circa 1960s; 2 Folders (Box 54)
      - [Friends, buildings, cats], undated (Box 54)
      - [Friends, family, readings, houses, ships, pets], 1959-2015, undated; 5 Folders (Box 56)
        Includes photographs of John Giglio, Ron Kelly, Midisel Gizzi, Clay Eshleman, and Scott Freedman.
      - [Friends, family, readings, pets], 1968-2004, undated; 2 Folders (Box 56)
      - [Friends, vacations], circa 1960s-1970s (Box 56)
      - Gerrit: larger images, including transparency for Fleicher portrait, circa 1960s-1999 (Box 56)
      - Gerrit and Harry Martin during the Latouche/Hammond years, circa 1960s (Box 56)
      - Gerrit and John Wieners [includes negatives], circa 1960s (Box 56)
      - Gerrit with Robert and Joby Kelly [includes negatives], 1968, undated (Box 56)
        Several envelopes of negatives are labeled Kelly, Oakley, Olson, and Di Prima.
      - Harry Martin, undated (Box 56)
      - Kenward Elmslie in photo booth, circa 1960s? (Box 56)
      - [Kenward] Elmslie's mother, Constance Pulitzer, with Gerrit Lansing's mother, Alice Scott, 1908 (Box 56)
      - Negatives, 1960, undated (Box 56)
      - Photo album, circa 1960s? (Box 56)
      - Photo album documenting Gerrit Lansing's library, 2018 (Box 57)
      - Photo album pages, 1912–1965 (Box 47)
      - Photo album pages, 1962, undated (Box 47)
      - Pictures with Gerrit, circa 1960s-2018; 2 Folders (Box 58)
        Includes photographs of Lansing with Ken Irby, Mary Roland, poet and bookstore owner Ifeanyi Menkiti, and various friends, as well as images of Lansing's childhood home and cats.
      - Places, houses, and shipyards, circa 1960s-1990s; 2 Folders (Box 58)